Hi all, good evening, hello Kavya and Roshan and you, I'm audible and visible guys, give
me thumbs up if you can hear me out, great, okay, good evening Sambit, good evening Abhishek,
hello, guys let me know if screen share is working, I'll just share it, is screen share
great, let's have seven minutes timer, we'll get started in seven minutes but
just want to know a few things before we get started with the class,
okay, I see some good amount of people joined so I just want to know a few things,
before this I have to share my iPad, give me a second quick time player,
where is this,
iPad is also fine right, you are able to see iPad screen,
okay great, so guys do let me know how many of you are able to maintain 90 and above PSP,
90 and above, if you are able to maintain 90 and above give me thumbs up, if not give me thumbs
down, okay great Abhinav, okay I see few people like give me thumbs up, so guys react it please,
let's need to know like how many, okay I'll write it down, PSP of 90% and above,
above 90% 99 great, okay so like I see only few people got reacted but there are two people who
are not able to maintain it, so guys can I help you out, do I have to contribute anything from my side,
because I just want you to you know, people I know that most of the people who are attending
my session are able to maintain 90 and above, just have seen few people who are not able to
like you know come up with like PSP percentage, because what I've seen is this LLD curriculum
right, this assignment problems hardly take half an hour to solve I guess,
30 minutes for a race class, not like DSA isn't it, like it's really you can complete it really
fast speed, okay so I would urge everyone right to keep it up as much as possible
and kudos to all of you like who are maintaining 90 and above, I've received personal comments
and chats, great work guys keep doing it, great so one thing I want to talk about is like last
how many of you were clear about the machine coding problems did we solve,
whether it's counter
or a star problem, star rating problem, does it find easy, easy enough like
are you able to relate it, code it, think in terms of solving a problem,
great I see three people reacting to it, guys can anyone drop a message in whatsapp chat,
my first class today excited, yeah excited as well, hope you have a great journey, great learning, so
we have still three minutes to go ahead, so anyone having any questions from the previous classes do
let me know if you have anything to ask for or anything you have concerns related to anything
like related to career or anything you have random points you can talk to me, so three minutes we'll
wait till then people join then once we once people join we'll get started,
you can talk to me for three minutes we'll wait till then people join then once we once people
join we'll get started, okay let me message it in the chat meanwhile
so
many people struggling to get full stack dev job,
okay yeah full stack dev is actually I would say tricky right because
when you talk about full stack as a profile right
there are two things front end focused
or back end focused
okay this is difficult to get it done because most of the back end systems whatever you see today
are focused on something which are related to java or you can say go lang like a whole
scaler is built on ruby and a part of it is having node js also you see there's a share between each
of them like like there are different shares from the back and when it comes to front end you most
preferred choice is react and then you have angular up to an extent where it goes to enterprise
or big companies okay but what we are picking up here to get our capability of full stack build
we picked it up murn stack such that we'll get good with front end and we'll have better idea
with node shares when you do this this is really easy out of the all the choices you have to
understand full end-to-end ecosystem only because it's based on completely javascript
as a core language once you learn js you will be able to deal with it okay but if you want to
go with different sorts of thing right it's really difficult so when you go for full stack
people are expecting a different combinations of things can you imagine it would be really
difficult for a person to combine and get a job okay but if you are particularly applying
on a react profiles you will get more options if you go for murn stack you'll see some options
so you have to pick and take it up you'll have a whole back end and front end things then depending
on company's requirement you can also learn new languages so you will be able to take it up one
by one okay so that's what i can tell from my experience okay
okay what about front end opportunities i see very less nowadays in scalar
front end opportunities okay i'm not exactly sure in scalar particularly from scalar
port placement portfolio but you have a good amount abundant amount of opportunities if you
go in any job or portfolio sites right you may be building the insta higher anything okay
can we have two event listeners for one element double click yes open there you can have it
uh whatever which is better for back end java springwood notches expresses abhishek i wouldn't
say that anything is better everyone is solving a different sort of problem uh you know one thing
if company needs other thing you should be in situation to like learn and write code it code
it down because when you go to for the product based companies language is not the skill that
people try to find it on the you are questioned on uh like your basics and ability to learn things
okay language is not the parameter on which product this works even if you're from java you
will be hired in microsoft because there's dot dot net they're working on if you know only golang
even then you can come to paypal where java works you can go to uber where golang is preferred but
you can if you know java node they'll take it so language is not a question when it goes to
bigger companies so you can pick it up anything and do it you should be in a situation to learn
from non-dick uh job experience when we should start looking for job after js react please go
after react at least please don't react uh build projects on that only after that try to apply it
because there's a one your portfolio will be also built up to the next step
uh you are a ux designer upendra then um i would say uh go with the front end def
if front end there would be easy and relatable for you like you will be able to relate more
right having a knowledge is good uh but uh on google stack but prefer to go with friend and
if you're coming into development compared to angular or react with this problem of course
react you can go and check github stars on uh either of the code bases but i think we have
elapsed the time guys we i don't see people jumping into today's class i'm not sure they say
anything specific okay okay uh back end is difficult right uh nothing is difficult it's
it's out of interest uh since if you see for friend and we started covering uh we started
covering from the basics right like if you see we started with html then css then js only then
we are moving to framework if you see combine all of these things front end will look difficult
go and ask someone back in person like is it do would you don't would do you want to do it
friend and he would avoid it okay uh okay so valentine celebrations are basic uh many people
avoided the class today can be anyways guys so i'll take few more questions if you have anything
related to career-based things i'll share my opinions on it hope uh you will be able to take
that and work towards better thing breakup is going on okay yeah then you can patch up again guys
hopefully so let's get started with today's class guys now in last class we started with machine
coding uh specifically uh type of questions uh a pattern of questions that can be asked in
uh like friend and lld interviews so if you see we picked two questions one was a counter
and one was a star rating problem so we'll move ahead from here so we'll build one a bit complicated
uh problem which is like nested comments so if you see in facebook or instagram you have
comment section where on one comment uh you'll be able to add your comment then you can add
another comment so you keep on replying to one chain so we'll try to replicate this particular
nested comment uh you know component right we'll try to implement and see what it takes to build
uh using simple html css js then we also have another question where you have to
you know play around with the otp like if you remember we have whenever you want to
enter into any otp you have boxes right uh four boxes or six boxes depending on it so how do
you build an interface and how do you manage an otp uh like entering field this would be really
basic but we'll be building this then we'll also build a progress bar uh when i say progress bar
it's just like low showing that loading uh like how much how you can build a progress bar where
you have let's say bar and then there's a loading filling it and then going back so we'll try to
implement these three things hopefully i'll try to make it as interesting as possible and as you
know i need your support keep keep on adding the comments that you have in your whatever thought
process you comes by when you see a question so excited guys let's start with the three questions
that we have because everything is you can see in the social media platform or everything you can
see across your any apps that you come across these components will be reflected okay so let's
uh not waste time here on the ipad let's move to the coding directly so first and foremost thing
i'll show what this nested components look like so we'll try to mimic it now i hope you can see
browser where you see the first comment let's say this is a dummy comment that has been added
and once there's an option that i can add a reply to it now once i click add reply do you see there's
an input element with a form input and there is a submit button now there here you can write some
let's say second comment uh i'm using some dummy content
okay now once you submit it what happens you see this a comment has been added
now what if i want to add a comment here again now do you see when i'm adding a comment i can add here
second comment so on one layer to the top comment you can add any number of comments and you can
also add if you want to reply to this one you can add it like a third comment third hyphen one
commentator okay so are you able to relate uh how this is going to work from a functionality point
of view like on one comment you can add a number of comments on again n comments you can keep on
add any number of comments at you so it's a chain that keeps on going building it's a really
relatable component you go into any social media app where likes and comment sections are available
there you will be able to see it can we create another parent comment section you can create
as much as much you wanted something but i was just focusing on like how do you relay
sub comments to the comment creating initial comment section is really easy
but the main problem really revolves around like how do you build this chain okay
so guys uh do you understand what we are uh yeah it's like creating a new ticket in the to do
something similar yeah uh you can say that yeah uh recursion will come to that uh
franco so we'll explore this possible steps like but let's let's as i say as we approached in last
class what we'll do is that once you have understood what's the requirement that we have to build
now we'll focus on building a layout for this one then a bit of css around it then we'll go
to the js part where we'll code down the logic for this i hope that point is clear guys
chalo let's let's approach that one uh
going back here uh i'll create a new class class 18
let's say uh we start with uh what i'll do okay let's let's build it in one file itself
i can say nested comments dot html okay now i'll add a dummy layout
i can give a title as nested comments
so one thing i'll do is like i'll minimize this one uh before this i'll open it in the preview
on the right side so that we can replicate that one now i'll close this for our sake now
now let's get started guys now one thing really common that we know is that anything that you are
building you you have something like a container revolving around it so i'll have a container or
dev container nothing else in that now comes you are you now it's your it's your game guys
you have to suggest me this let's let's uh just focus on this part as of now
first comment is static so let's build the static part now what do you think
where how we should get started with this part
uh h2 and the spandead uh
one thing let's say uh do you see this is a first uh again a container i don't say it's a diff
container somebody is going for h2 uh which is like he's trying to add this then then there is
something like add reply now let's say uh what it takes what we'll try to build this one and we'll
try to see you uh so i have some approach in my mind i'll try to show it to you let's say i have
a comment container let's say this is a container where all comments will be there like okay first
level comment whichever we are which is this is this part specifically now let's say if you see
this is like a card which is having a box shadow are you able to relate this one this is a card
which is having a box shadow so let's let's do that firstly inside comments container i'll have
like let's say i say all comments in it which will have all comments inside this i'll create a div
with a card first okay till now i haven't done anything so i created a comment section then i
went to all comments i created a card just uh subreading the concerns of containers now now comes
uh like we can have a span tag or we can go with a h2 tag if we if we are providing
see your styles for this one we can go with span tag and we can deal with this
let's say first commentator i just add this
okay let's say i also give a class uh called as a text because this is just a simple text
what we are adding we'll have a common css for this one added down the line now then we have
a span tag with a reply uh you know uh span which we say that add reply
now okay this is what we have designed till now then other than this card other than this card
we also have something like once you click add reply you have simple two things okay uh input
element and submit event submit button let's try to replicate that one too
uh so what we'll do here is that inside all comment section below the cards i'll do something like
dev uh comments let's say reply container
once i have this container inside this thing i have again same input element
uh let's say type equal to text okay it didn't work let's say again uh input element
type text then also you have a button a submit button so for this one i'll say button submit
submit okay on a top level this is what we have right let's say i have a class btm and then
for input element again uh we have let's say if you see here uh write your reply is something
we are showing it inside uh add reply is clickable huh yes it's clickable if you see
i'm moving or cursor it is pointing it if i click it only then i'm able to create it caveat
okay then once i have this uh i'll have a placeholder here which says
write your reply
okay once i have write your reply now on a top level on a top really top level we have addressed
like uh what a particular uh basic layout would look like right because this is where we'll have
because this is where we'll have uh like let's say
already added comment
and this will help us to create new comments
comments right this is a basic idea that we had now let's let's go and try to make
a bad bit styles to this one uh one thing i can do it like do you do you want me to add styles
here itself or create a separate file because this will have a large amount of css guys that
we have to address what would you prefer guys
here is fine okay let's let's do it here itself so first and foremost thing i'll go around and
play around with the card now if you see this card css are specifically uh we can create a
new file i'll i'll copy it and create it there guys once we understand it while we create there
okay now let's say we have this card now we are adding uh css to this one so first and foremost
thing do you see uh box shadow we'll add a box shadow to this one uh let's say
now do you remember guys what are the different fields of box shadow gives
guys
horizontal vertical shadow how much shadow do you need
and like how much like how where do you want to bend that particular thing then
so i have prepared this one so i'm entering the values directly but now let's see if this is
looking like a orbit shadow or will have a color to it so that you can be able to see uh understand
this one let's say background color rgb let's say i have triple two triple two triple two so that
you will be able to see a hash color added please repeat the box shadow units okay let's let's do
this one let's copy this one
now if you see i'm selecting this thing and as i told you like if you want to play around with
a box shadow you can always select uh like if you see it here now when i click here now if you see
offset x offset if i play around if i make it make it 10 pixel let's say 10 pixel now do you see any
change here so uh let's say if i make other things let's say around the y-axis
do you see a shadow which is moving across directions when i'm moving it around
direction of shadow along the x-axis y-axis now those are the first two values then
you have a blur effect how much blur you need it okay how many pixels of blur you need it then
you have something like spread how long you want to spread this shadow i hope you are able to see
this guys uh right firstly x and y axis where you want to move the shadow then how much amount
of blur you want that shadow to be then how long you want to spread that shadow okay all these
fields now if i refresh it currently this is how it looks like okay once i added i added here
till now only two fields a background color so that we can see the box elevated and a box shadow
now once we have done this let's let's go and someone suggested me to add a border radius
i'll give let's say 0.8 rem okay once i have this yeah it's look too much curved let's say 6 rem
still let's look too much curved
0.4 works
once we have this let's say i want some differentiator from top i'll give a 10
pixel differentiator and like getting something margin and let's say also i have padding across
sites like around the sites i have some padding four sites 10 pixel around the main this this item
okay once i have this let's say also do i need height or it is automatically taken like i have
to have to specify height what if what if i give height as auto what do you think the value will
be applied if i make it auto what do you think auto will make it
anything guys anyone having any idea some which has same value
pradeep says auto but can anyone guess like
so it will automatically calculate as per like you know the container and like firstly according
to the screen size right it will be automatically calculating exact height that is applied now you
can always go and see here what is the exact height that is being calculated using like computer step
using like computer step okay also i think here also you'll be able to see
width is available but height if you see 18 pixel this got automatically applied calculating
when you have auto now if i reduce the screen size let's say if i show you how this works
if i reduce the screen size
since uh this is about height that's maximum it is uh minimum it is taking but i hope you generally
have an idea like how does auto works it's calculating based on the content
okay i will come to that part but now let's move to the second thing uh where you want to
add color so i would say that let's say i have reply now i can i if i what if i want to apply
uh just a second guys
if you see it here inside inside this card you have something like add reply
this card you have something like add reply okay let's pick this css apply css for this one dot
reply inside this now what what sort of colors do we see like if you come in here uh see it here
now if i don't want to let's say if i want to make this as a color this color particular color
let me go here and i'll do like i have a color already so rgb now i hope everyone remembers rgb
i read green blue percentages like how many percentages we need and all those stuff
of combination of them which gives you
color now if you see that color has been exactly applied then okay yeah cursor should be pointer
uh as some it says then can i make font weight as bolder
so that it looks a bit bold now that's fine but let's add you know if you see it here for
the text part let's add some you know if the text is holding for this all the parts now if you see
so let's have some content for this one i'll go and select text and on this i'll say that hey
can i make display block so that what if okay let's say i make a display block and i give font size as
20 pixel to resemble that one and they'll say i'll say font weight as a bolder
no that's fine do i need display block if i can convert this into div instead of a span my problem
would be solved is it isn't it why do i need a span
doesn't make any sense to have a spandex you know let's say i convert this also into div
let's say i convert this also into div
because it doesn't really make we convert a particular thing into other things now so
is this clear firstly to everyone like how we managing this one
like first part we created a cards container where we have two things first commentator and
add reply so if we went on to first select the card on this card we added box shadow
border radius background color margin top adding height right some basic basic fields
now add reply now let's say we want to change this now do you see one differentiator that
there's always a gap coming for the next level element for the each level let's say i write down
if you see i write it down here for each level the next element whichever child element we are
creating it it it moves somewhat on the right side right now how can you think like we cannot
achieve this how can you what can how is it possible for us to achieve this just think of it
here we have everything can anyone think of any idea left margin is absolutely right but
on which element you will apply left margin margin left how would you apply
for each and every element opendra think of that thing like how would you apply margin left
for each of the new incoming child element so one hint i want to give you is that we have to use a
pseudo selector we can add margin using j's parent matching plus one rib
uh okay the rest that's one of the way we can do it but think of like can we do it
simply using a pseudo selector how many of you remember n child or nth number
or that sort of thing like how we can access or if you have a multiple child using a parent
container and then trying to get the children's elements out of it now there is a new pseudo
selector that we might have might not have got exposed to it let's say i'm selecting all comments
okay all comments inside that all comments i'm selecting i'm saying that other than
other than first child can you apply margin first for the each and every child
can i say this this way
okay and i give as for them
other than first child apply margin left to each of the child
do you see it here like are you able to relate it because this is the first child card then the
other child is like comments other than the first child apply margin left to the each and every
next level containers but now do you see that is being applied
okay did i make any spelling mistakes here
okay why i cannot see it class applied here
so
can anyone think of like where we are failing like let's say
if i try to search with this in the chrome browser
not first child selector
okay see this is the same representation that we are using we are selecting a particular element
other than for that one except first child give it all get all okay let's see
if i go to all comments computer styles okay we'll come to that where the whites not applying it
but let's try to make no problem okay just follow up okay so first thing and foremost
like let's go to the simple one we'll come back to this one where we are applying it to the
child what we'll do is like if you see inside this container we also have a button class
let's try to make a button look the way we want if you go back and see it in the actual app
it's just adding a border radius color white and you know the color that we have it for add reply
we have to copy that so let's go let me go and copy the color part
and make it as a background color and let me give color as white
and let me copy border radius also
okay now once we had this then we had something like let's say if you go and see it here
padding yeah let's add some padding around it
padding of three pixel around then i can say that i also don't need a border firstly border zero
because it's giving a black in color which is i don't need it for the button then also i can add
a box shadow right uh like there's a box shadow elevated which is like really less box shadow
let's say i go back onto the top i copy the same box shadow that i have for comment section i copy
i copy and keep it here now all this is fine all this is fine but
do we see any change in this color or like it's larger and lighter let's make a bit change
this is fine anyways now coming back to uh do we need anything else guys here on the button give
border radius to input text also yeah we'll we'll go to the input text let's say we have a class
input i'll select the class input on this input let me give something
a particular uh firstly border radius of you can say 0.4 rem once we have this then you can we can
always add let's say i have a specific height of 25 pixel to show it now i have colored both the
things like uh button and input now let's go to this container level i should have come in
the reverse direction let me go to the container now let's talk about this container guys what we
should be having in the container to make it reflect like as it was looking earlier
now we see that this is not applying what if i remove and i say that hey all the containers
wherever you see this one uh keep a margin left of four them right because i've seen that
uh they should have applied i tried it but maybe we'll fix this one so uh what i'm doing is like
so uh what i'm doing is like i'm selecting the child kind of size then once we have this then
let's say any other things guys should i give margin top of 0.4 rem anything else
guys
do they look good enough
do they look good enough let's make uh increase the height of it bit
let's make this as a 30 pixel and also button let's add some height to this button
uh height of 30 pixel
okay and let's increase this as a 0.6 to reflect uh like the same way now
padding to the button do we need a padding to the button we had three pixel
let's make it five okay okay cool no no risk guys uh now let's see like if i even if i give
some margin right so that they look differentiated to pixel on the left cool now this is clear right
a basic css that we applied uh and we created for the two elements uh any doubts anyone having
any doubts on this because this is something really straightforward all the properties we
have learned cuts cursor to the button great one uh cursor pointer i hope no one have any
challenge understanding these two things right now we'll go to the actual js part now if you see
firstly tell me something this will be static or it should be
generated dynamically from the js part on click of add reply
dynamically right now let's approach this one step by step okay i'll go below now firstly
i'll create a script tag uh now what are the two events that we are handling it here firstly what
are the two events that we are handling if i refresh it one is like add reply and there is
on click of submit right i understand click uh and everything now uh sorry uh when it comes
to event i got it but two main core functionalities that i was talking about
both the events are click i agree with your point uh
click on replay click on submit right two things now on click of reply what we are doing it
we are creating this input element right input element uh and submit button
on click of reply we are doing this right on click of submit we are building this first comment
or like uh this this particular box and shared isn't it so you are able to what i'm trying to
say is that firstly not only you build dynamically this particular input element and separate but you
also have to dynamically generate on click of submit this particular box shadow and same thing
reflecting whatever we have built it a card are you able to relate that we need both card
and common supply container to be generated dynamically so for that thing for that thing
i want to write two things like there are let's say we create two functions firstly creating input
box okay for replying it like if you let's say i click off reply whenever you click a reply
you need something like this box so let's say you have a function uh create input box and i'll leave
it just firstly we won't write any logic in that we'll just write down the out layer firstly okay
what all things we needed then also we have something like
can i say a function create comment
or comment box or i can say
add reply let's say we say this way add reply so this will create
it comment
and add reply to it button two okay so these are the two events that we have to toggle right on
click of something we have to trigger to these two functions and these two functions should be
handling all the use cases isn't it this is this general idea are everyone able to follow up
like on click of anything now now let's do that same drill of handling the click firstly now
let's say i have a const and i'll say that i'll get an access to comment container
document dot query selector inside this i have to let's say now the trick comes right the problem
here is that you should be able to listen all the
yeah i'll come to that caveat so okay let me re-explain it now you have two events firstly
when you click on add reply you're creating an input element and submit button so for that thing
whenever you click on this thing i have to write logic in this create input box is this clear
like what does we mean when i say input box what i meant it now then if there is something user
entered it and clicking submit we need to create this comment right comment and add reply button
so for that one we'll have this function once you enter the data and click submit
so two functions solving both the problems now when it comes to query selector what event we
will be listening to is if you see here we have to listen all the ad replies in the whole page
right because we can click here this button anytime we can click this button anytime we
can click this button to anytime right any any ad reply button we should be able to listen
and newly generated too so now for that reason now let's say i'll use that event bubbling concept
okay using event bubbling what should be the thing that we should be selecting it
what is a parent of all the things
first parent from the bubbling concept like when you go for it by default it's a bubbling whenever
you add an event listener so what should be the first parent that you see here
a parent class that will be targeting
let's say comment container
right let's pick this one let's pick this one okay let's pick comment container
so now on this comment container we'll be able to listen all the events that are happening on
this buttons right any button anything you click will be able to figure it out
right anything that's happening in whole page will be able to figure out in the comment container
because this is a parent for the whole page
guys are you able to relate why i'm selecting comment container here
is anyone if there is anyone let me know if someone is not understanding why did we pick it up
okay i see two people cool please keep responding so that i understand that whether you are able
to follow up or not both some bits not didn't understand great so coming back to this one guys
why not main container you pick it anything you pick it anything even if you want to pick
it up this one all comments you can be pick it you can pick it this container also
you can pick it anything as people suggested here in the chat that's why i picked it one thing
okay now why i have to select any of like a parent container this reason
because if i click on any reply let's say i click on this reply i should be able to listen if i
click on this reply i should be able to listen if i click on this i should be able to listen
now if why should i add a event listener to each one of them so for that reason since this is
a one logic that we want to handle it i am saying is that anyways you click on any event if you had
a event listener to the parent and you are listening to the click event you will be able to you know
handle there at that particular position right that's the reason why i was asking like which
parent container should we select okay so i'm picking up a comment container also you can pick
it up all content all comments you can pick it up this container also since these are parent level
hierarchy you can pick it up anything somewhere did you get this point why i'm trying to access
that particular thing now i'll it will be more clear when we actually debug this one okay now
let's say now let's say i i go and add a listener to this one comment container dot add event
listener i'm listening to the click event let's say i have a function okay and i have an event here
i let's say i close this now now console dot lock let's say uh i'm just trying to print event
let's say i'm saying that someone is click something now if you go to this project right
and open the console even if i click add reply event will be printed even if i click submit
it even if i click submit event will be printed that's the reason leveraging or even bubbling
i've added it to the parent container and then i'm listening to both the things is this point here
guys how why i'm adding to it parent level now what if instead of comment container i'll give
it to all comments even if i do this i should be able to listen events right
even if i do this i would be able to listen all of this
is this clear there is no difference if you select anything even bubbling will go to the
topmost element from the root target element so that's the reason why i'm selecting any of the
containers let's say we select this common container itself which is the parent for the
all the comments okay now once we have this once we have this
let's say you uh from this event if we try to get
okay uh let's build like how would you listen to add reply or create submit will come to that part
but let's fix uh build this one because that's the how would you add a listener to each and
everything would be a bit tricky i'll come to that part let's let's build add reply here first
when you are creating uh add reply like this is the content let's say this is something you are
trying to build expect that you will receive some text inside this function uh what i'm trying to
do is start let's say uh again a simple logic where firstly i'll create an element uh let's
say element and i'll say the document dot create element i'll give a diff okay and inside that
i'll also have a element dot let's say set attribute inside this attribute i'll add a
particular class which will say all comments now if you see this i'm adding all comments here
here
inside this all comments i'll write down the whole inner html part
now inside this inner html i'll write simple basically i'll copy whatever thing you see it
here that card uh example i'll copy this i'll put it here once i have this also i'll
make it this one as a dynamic adding a text here and once i'm build this element i have to append
this element so but what i'll do is that i'll return this particular uh element that created
whatever we created uh so that i have element dot inner html is this clear guys like how we are
creating add reply i'm just copy paste and created that element i'm returning from this
nothing new it's just that i'm replicating whatever we have done it on top now for
consider this one if you want to create an input box how would you create an input box
for creating input box we don't need any parameter uh like here because it's just
that it's a simple input like this both things so but we have this particular class we have to
create a day for that one let's say again i create a const element simple document dot create element
inside that i select as a dev and once i have this element i'll say that element dot set attribute
inside that i say that i want to add a class and inside this i'll i'll have this class
uh sorry this class added once i have this then i'll go to this element dot inner html inside this
let's say i add all the things that i have it here two things
right once we do this i'll also return div from here or element from here
right so i hope this is clear this is pretty basic right uh like whatever we have done there
we have replicated so i hope these functions are clear to everyone
anyone having any challenge understanding these functions or the html css part we did till now
anyone having any challenge now what i'll do is that i'll comment this one because we have to
let's say we have to create this container or call this call this input box
create input box function when you click a reply right when you click a reply you should be able
to call this and append to the dom right now now think of it how would you do that one how would
you do that one how would you know what who has clicked and what
now just like everything it will be is before your eyes you we have done this multiple times
i just want you to think it like how can we access it
can i say that if if particular let's say this if you see add reply if you click on this particular
div or uh like if someone is clicking something or text or a container and if that particular
element is having a class of reply we will call this one can i say that text this is a dynamic
value right when we are creating an ad reply this comment should be coming from the text
i'll come to that some with how that works
so somebody says e dot target dot class name
if it is having a reply call that function right how many of you think that would be
right way to do it
this idea are you able to follow up are you able to follow up with my idea
so let's say that what somebody is suggesting let me do that uh e dot target dot class name
let's say out of this uh instead of class name or what if we get a class list
uh and let's say i say that if it is containing
since this is a class list will give you an array of elements uh because sometimes it's
better to use class list rather than a particular class name and we can say that if it is containing
reply if it is containing reply then call that function so i'll say that get me that element
element how would i get this element i'll say that create input box
okay i'll create this input box and now where should i append it
where should i append this one once i have this element
which will be returned from this one where should i append it comments container
and let's say i say that as you say comment container dot append child element now let's
say if i do this let's see this what could be the behavior of this one if i click add reply
that's cool if i click add reply that's cool it's working fine right
guys are you able to understand how we are able to achieve this part firstly
simple basic uh thing right adding a listener and listening to a class now let's say if a
particular event if a particular event e.target.classlist contains
now if you see here when you click a button you have a class button right if there is
if there is something someone is clicking a button then we'll have this one no firstly
once we have this now you have to get the text let's say if i even if i want to call the const
element if i want to call this function where we are trying to create add reply i have to pass on
the content text into it like what user is writing it down okay let's say then simple again
comments dot append child element same line i have written it but now when i click a add reply
when i click a add reply i have the text here no the text is getting added into this one right
this element or sorry this input element which is having class input
so what i can do it here is that if i need that text whatever user is entering
i can say const text document dot query selector get me the text
can i say this guys
out of after getting that text now what i have to get out of that value
get input dot value says some bit simple text dot value or else let's say i say this as an
input element input element i can say input element dot value
guys are you able to follow up whatever i'm saying it
now let's see this this got failed now can anyone help me out where we might have
okay this is firstly this is not in text this is an input because here we added
class input item was type text okay now let's say i created something i click submit i'm able to add
it that's fine but are you able to see a particular thing let's say if i try to check this one if i
try to do all the comments all other comments other than the first child like when i say this
this is other than this container other than the first container whatever subsequent containers
that you're creating it should have a margin of four uh margin left of four so let's say if i
create this i'm able to do this one but do you see something that we have to remove
we pass the param into the function right here we pass that param into the function
but here when i'm clicking submit i have to do something what i have to do
okay someone says that hey are you that content is not being updated the content is not being
updated whatever you have entered here that